噢 你好像刚参加完一场婚礼
Oh, you look like you're coming from a wedding.
是一场很棒的婚礼吗
Was it a nice one?
额 这个故事有点长 我不想太没礼貌
Uh, it's a long story, and I don't mean to be rude,
但我真的很不想讲这个故事
but I really don't feel like talking about it.
这一切都开始于新娘要见我
It all started when the bride asked to see me...
哇哦
Wow.
好了 别敷衍我了 莫斯比
Okay, don't sugarcoat it, Mosby.
直说吧 好吗
Just give it to me straight, okay?
巴尼现在被吓成什么样了
How bad is Barney freaking out right now?
哦 他挺好的
Oh, he's fine.
说真的 他真的挺好的
No, I'm serious. He's totally fine.
我家里有条更好的领带
I have a better tie at home!
是菊蓝色的
It's cornflower blue!
是矢车菊蓝色的啊
你放心吧 巴尼?斯丁森绝绝对对的
You may rest assured, Barney Stinson is absolutely 100%
能撑的过去这场婚礼
going through with this wedding.
好吧
Okay.
这是好消息
Good news.
额 只是有个小小的问题
Um, just one small issue, uh...
我撑不过去
I can't go through with this wedding.
老爸老妈浪漫史
第八季  第一集
翻译:  加菲猪 Kevin Abby Roy
后期+统筹: 加菲猪 Roy 校对: 园丁姐姐 小草莓
HIMYM字幕组倾情奉献
冷静下 每个人在他们结婚那天
Okay, calm down, everyone feels this way
都会有这样的感觉
on their wedding day.
都会过去的
It'll pass.
不 它越来越厉害了
No.It's more than that.
我有个很严肃的问题
I'm having a serious crisis.
我在想爬出这个窗户是不是很难
And I wonder if it would be hard to climb out that window.
嗯 爬出去简单
Uh, climbing out's easy.
爬进来才是真正的挑战
Climbing in's the real challenge.
哦 对了
Oh, right.
这是同一个窗户是吧
It's the same window, isn't it?
是的
Yeah.
那个故事发生在2012年5月
That story transpired in May of 2012.
来回忆一下 莉莉和马修灰常的开心
As you may recall, Lily and Marshall were gloriously happy
开心他们刚刚迎来你们的哥哥马尔文
having just welcomed your cousin Marvin.
巴尼和奎恩也灰常的开心
While Barney and Quinn were gloriously happy
开心他们刚刚订婚了
having just gotten engaged.
还有罗宾 好吧
And Robin, well...
啊 抠到了
Ah, got it!
天啊 这个小贱货从早餐起就在这里了
Man, that sum'bitch had been in there since breakfast!
罗宾对阵罂粟籽 一比零
Robin one, poppy seed: zero.
见鬼 要来点香槟了
Heck, this calls for some champagne.
好像冰箱里有一些
I think there's some in the fridge.
我们去拿
We'll get it.
我们一定不会在厨房里爱爱的
We're totally not gonna go have sex in the kitchen,
正如你们所想的那样
if that's what you're thinking.
啊 我们不要?
Aw, we're not?
不 我们当然要了 我已经把你的胸罩脱掉了
No, no, we are. I already took off your bra.
好吧
Oh!
喂 你们俩确定你们还能来点香槟
Hey, are you guys sure you can handle champagne?
你们好像一周左右都没有睡觉了
You haven't slept in like a week.
虽然才是一晚上
We should just call it a night.
哦 我知道这是为什么了
Oh, I see what this is about.
巴尼订婚了你觉得很怪
You feel weird because Barney's engaged.
你说啥
What?!
不 当然不了
No. Of course not.
我来告诉你为什么不觉得怪
And I will tell you why it's not weird.
什么不觉得怪
What's not weird?
巴尼订婚的事实
The fact that Barney's engaged.
巴尼订婚了?!
Barney's engaged?!
见鬼 要来点香槟了
Heck, this calls for some champagne.
我觉得冰箱里有一些
I think there's some in the fridge.
我的天哪 你们俩为什么就是不承认
Oh, my God, why don't you both just admit it:
你们已经完全精疲力尽了
You're deliriously exhausted.
我们好好的
We're fine!
真的吗
Really?
我们才不会成为那种一有了孩子
We're not gonna be the kind of people who have a baby
就完全变成僵尸的人
and become total zombies.
是啊 罗宾
Yes, Robin.
我们才不会成为那种
We're not gonna be the kind of people
一旦有了僵尸 就完全变成孩子的人
that have a zombie and become total babies.
好吧 我想说的是...
Okay, well, what the I was saying is...
你们明白了吗
Do you understand?
明白 绝对的明白
Yes! God, yes!
你不用多费口舌了 妹子
You are preaching to the choir, sister.
喔
Whew!
-喂  -所以
-Hey. -So...
我正在想我的婚礼
I am thinking about my bridal party
嗯 我没有很多女性朋友
and, uh, I don't have a lot of girlfriends.
我的意思是 我有工作上的朋友
I mean, I have work friends,
但是我在脱衣舞俱乐部工作
but I worked at a strip club
我知道她们一定会抱怨
and I know they'll just complain
伴娘礼服露得太少了 所以
about any bridesmaid's dress that has a front, so...
你们愿不愿意做我的伴娘
Would you guys be my bridesmaids?
愿意 我好荣幸
I'd be honored. Yes!
不包括你 马修
Not you, Marshall.
但是 耶 谢谢
But, yay, thank you! Oh.
-谢谢  -天哪
-Oh, thank you. -Oh, my gosh.
一定会好有爱的
It's gonna be so much fun.
好吧 现在觉得怪了
Yeah, now it's weird.
什么觉得怪
What's weird?
我 当奎恩的伴娘
Me being Quinn's bridesmaid.
我一点也不担心 亲爱的
Oh, I wouldn't worry about that, sweetie.
她可能都不会邀请你呢
She probably won't even ask you.
她刚刚才邀请我
She just did.
我们俩都答应了
And we both said yes.
见鬼 要来点香槟了
Heck, this calls for some champagne.
我觉得冰箱里还有一些
I think there's some in the fridge.
与此同时 我也非常的开心
Meanwhile, I was also gloriously happy,
和维多利亚向落日驶去
Driving off into the sunset with Victoria,
她为我在圣坛上抛下了她的未婚夫克劳斯
Who left her fiance Klaus at the altar for me.
但还是有一个问题
There was just one problem.
我想知道克劳斯现在有没有看到你的字条
I wonder if Klaus found your note yet.
我的字条
My note?
是啊 就像
Yeah, you know,
我要离开你了 之类的字条
The "I'm leaving you at the altar" Note.
那很重要吗
Is that a thing?
当你在圣坛前抛弃某人 你总得留一张字条
When you leave someone at the altar, you always leave a note.
这是基本的礼节嘛
It's common courtesy.
我认为这基本礼节已经在我从那扇窗户那里跑出去的时候消失了
I think common courtesy went out the window when I did.
你看 当斯黛拉在圣坛抛弃我的时候
Look, when Stella left me at the altar,
至少我还得到了一个解释
At least I got an explanation.
我是说 那张字条让你保持理智
I mean, that note is what keeps you sane.
你读一遍 再读一遍 你把上面的内容记得清清楚楚
You read it, you re-read it, you memorize it,
你把字条放在身边入睡 你闻着它
You sleep with it, you sniff it
因为那张字条还有一些她的的味道
Because it still kind of smells like her,
到最后
And then, finally...
你放手了（也有扔出去的意思）
You let it go...
把它绑在板砖上 直接扔向
Tied to a brick, right through her perfect
她郊区小屋的玻璃上
Little suburban bay window.
好吧 我现在就给他发短信
I'll just text him.
你必须要留字条
You're leaving a note.
现在 巴尼和我
So, Barney and I have already disagreed
在一些婚礼细节上有些分歧
On a few of the wedding details.
我想在婚礼上搞自助餐
I want to go with a buffet,
但他想在婚礼上骑着灰熊过走道
And he wants to ride down the aisle on a grizzly bear.
它会穿礼服的
He'll be wearing a tux.
好吧 好吧 为了你我就改骑熊猫吧
Fine, fine, I'll settle for a panda bear,
但是必须要你给我的裁缝打电话
But you have to call my tailor.
他一定会因为这次改动非常生气的
He'll be furious about the switch.
嘿 巴尼 那个
Hey, Barney, uh...
我们需要谈一谈
We've gotta talk.
那个 奎恩刚刚邀请我做她的伴娘
Um, Quinn just asked me to be one of her bridesmaids.
她甚至一点都不认为
Isn't she even a little
我们曾经约会过而感到别扭
weirded out that you and I used to date?
奎恩的字典里根本就没有嫉妒这个词
Quinn doesn't have a jealous bone in her body.
她逆来顺受
She rolls with the punches.
-她... -根本不知道
-She... -Doesn't have a clue.
的确 她不知道
No, she does not.
写好了
Okay.
好
克劳斯 我真的很难用语言描述
"Klaus, there is no easy way to tell you
我今天不能嫁给你的原因
Why I won't be marrying you today.
祝你夏天愉快 维多利亚
Have a great summer, Victoria."
就这点
That's it?
不 不行 我们要把这件事情办好
No, no, we gotta do this right.
但 这个不能你写啊
Well, you can't write it.
瞄一眼就知道 这明显是男人的笔迹（泰德以前学过花体字）
One look, it's gonna be obvious it's a guy's handwri...
哦 好吧 现在没事了
Oh no, we're good.
好吧 好吧 你写 我提意见
Okay, fine, you write, I'll advise.
克劳斯
"Klaus."
你就直呼其名么
Just "Klaus"?
别闹了 有点爱心 这家伙已经很可怜了
Come on, give it some heart, the poor guy.
亲爱的克劳斯
"Dear sweet Klaus..."
亲爱的 怎么 你还爱着那个混蛋
"Sweet?" What, are you still in love with this jerk?
我自个写
I'm doing this on my own.
对不起 我就是
I'm sorry, I just...
就是 为这个家伙感到抱歉
You know, I feel bad for the guy.
我正在从他身边抢走这个世界上最完美的女人
I'm stealing the greatest girl in the world away from him.
不是你抢走了我
You're not stealing me.
是我选择了你
I'm choosing you.
因为你爱我
Because you are loving
你关心我
And you are caring...
并且 你要把这张字条送过去
And you are going to go deliver this note.
等等 你想让我送过去
Wait, you want me to go in there?
今天 我放弃了所有
It took everything I had to climb out
从那个教堂的窗户爬出来
That church window today.
但 如果我就这样回去了
And if I have to go back in there,
我不确定我会再走出来
I'm not sure I can do it again.
这样会让字条闻起来有你的味道
It has to smell like you.
所以 奎恩一点也不知道我们曾约会过
So Quinn has no idea that we used to date?
一点也不知道
None whatsoever.
好吧 巴尼 你想想
Okay, Barney, think this through.
你真的想
Do you really want to
在你和奎恩的生活里...
spend the rest of your life with Quinn...
哦 天啊 你说到点上了
Oh, God, you have a point.
还没呢
Haven't gotten to it yet.
好的 继续
Of course. Continue.
你真的想要和奎恩共度余生
Do you really want to spend the rest of your life with Quinn
并隐藏这个秘密
And keep this secret?
我的意思是说 她会发现的
I mean, she's gonna find out.
奎恩不会发现的 因为我把它们都销毁了
Quinn's not gonna find out because I've destroyed
你和我曾在一起的时候所有的证据
Every piece of evidence that you and I were ever a couple.
这也太扯了吧
That's ridiculous.
你不可能把它们全都销毁了
You couldn't have gotten rid of all of it.
你用一张老虎的照片代替了我
You replaced me with a tiger.
我不能把你完全P掉
I couldn't completely get you out of that one.
我就只能自己创造一些了
Had to get creative.
好吧 很高兴你把我们在一起的整个时光都给删除了
Well, I'm glad that deleting our entire time together
这个对你来说这个太容易了
Was so easy for you.
但是我向你保证 奎恩总会发现的
But I guarantee you: Quinn is gonna find out eventually.
不 她不会的
No, she won't.
但我需要你的帮助
I just need your help.
我也需要你们两个人的帮助
Yours, too.
我知道你们两个和这件事情没有关系
I know you're out of it,
但是你要向我保证 绝对不告诉奎恩
But you have to promise not to tell Quinn, okay?
告诉她什么
Tell Quinn what?
回答正确
Exactly.
不 她真的在问你 没有装傻
No, she's really asking.
-哥没法爬下水道 -为啥
-Can't climb the drainpipe. -What?
四年级时，我在体育课上
When I was in fourth grade, I couldn't climb the rope
没爬上绳子 然后所有同学都取笑我
in gym class and all the other kids made fun of me,
再说那也不是我的错
even though it wasn't my fault.
我要在阿三后面爬上去
I had to go after Efthimios Papajapoulos.
而那时绳子上已经沾满了羊油
The rope was slick with lamb grease!
好吧 那走正门啊
Okay, so just walk in the front door
就像那是你家
and act like you belong.
拿好
Here.
这是换衣间的钥匙
Here's the key to the dressing room.
你想干啥
Can I help you?
我是教堂里打杂的
Hi. I'm the church handyman.
这里有东西坏了要我修
I'm here to fix the broken thing.
它爆掉了
It's busted.
新娘要打个小盹
The bride is taking a "Schnooze."
她让我看着 不希望任何人打扰到她
She asked me to stand watch so that no one disturbs her.
我会很快的
I'll be quick.
那你也会死的很快的
You will be dead.
姐以前是在莱比锡玩摔跤的
I used to wrestle in Leipzig.
算了
You know what?
字条什么的挺多余的
A note's redundant.
你不在 他懂的
You're not there. He gets it.
不行 你说得对 我必须得留张字条
No, you were right, I have to leave a note.
这是基本礼节啊
It's common courtesy.
好吧 那也不可能啊
Well, it's not gonna be possible
有个熊腰虎背的女门神杵在那里
with Andrea the Giant standing guard up there.
噢 对 克劳斯的妹妹
Oh, right, Klaus's sister.
巴尼在就好了
It's too bad Barney's not here.
这男人就是为了伴娘们而存在的
Man, he lives for bridesmaids.
是啊 不在啊
Right, but he's not.
再说了 他也做不到靠打电话就能色诱妹子啊
And it's not like he could seduce Uta over the phone.
接受挑战
Challenge accepted!
如果就只是电话的话就不算偷腥了对吧
Honey, it's not cheating if it's on the phone, right?
你刚说了什么
Say what now?
奎恩同意了
Quinn's on board!
把她手机号发我
Text me her number!
你个猥琐的下流胚
You filthy, disgusting man!
不过好吧 你说的东西我还是会照做的
But yes, I will do that to myself at your instruction.
先让我找到储藏室
Let me find a broom closet.
嗯 是 很好
Oh, ja, good.
我成功了 成功了
I did it. I did it!
你太神奇了
You're amazing.
我们走吧
Let's get out of here.
我把车钥匙落换衣间里了
I left the car keys in the dressing room.
而且我一关上门它就自己锁掉了
Pretty sure the door locked behind me.
天啊 额滴神啊
Oh, God... Oh, God... Oh, God...
巴尼认为我不能保守秘密
I found it kind of insulting that Barney doesn't
他也太看不起我了
think we can keep this secret.
我是说 没错 马尔文整得我们整夜睡不了
I mean, yeah, Marvin's keeping us up all night.
但是他依旧是全城最美的女孩子
But he's still the prettiest little girl in the city.
亲爱的你知道你刚刚说了什么吗
Baby, did you just hear yourself?
你说全城最漂亮的女孩子
You said, "Prettiest little girl in the city."
应该是全国才对哈
I think you meant "Country""
嗯嗯
Yeah.
我说 巴尼他怎么想的
I mean, what does Barney think?
好像我们马上就要抖出他之前
We're just gonna blurt out that he used to date...
嘘
Shh!
我去 那个好险啊
Oh... that was close.
奎恩有可能会通过这玩意儿听见的
Quinn could've heard us through the...
真及时
Good catch!
我刚刚差点就要把巴尼和罗宾好过那档子事抖出来了
I almost just blurted out that Barney used to date Robin!
巴尼之前真把过罗宾
Barney used to date Robin?!
你啥时候进来的
When did you get in here?
在十分钟前 你们说
Like, ten minutes ago when you said,
奎恩 咱们去小马尔文的房间里玩吧
"Hey Quinn, let's all go hang out in Marvin's room."
再会 小姐
Auf wiedersehen, fraulein.
听我说 我是讨厌把人物模式化
You know, I hate to perpetuate the stereotype,
但来自德国萨克森州的女摔跤手就是那么的典型
but German female wrestlers from Saxony are just begging for it.
你泡过罗宾吗
You dated Robin?
艹
Verdammt!
抱歉我说了谎 我会告诉你所有的事
I'm sorry I lied to you. I'll tell you everything
-整个故事    -好 在我走去这扇门之前
-The whole story. -Fine. You have one minute
你有一分钟的时间
before I walk out that door.
这个 故事有点略长啊 奎恩
Um, it's, uh, kind of a long story, Quinn.
得用不止一分钟了
Gonna take a bit little longer than a minute.
还剩52秒
52 seconds.
七年前 马修莉莉初订婚
Seven years ago, when Marshall and Lily got engaged,
泰德人群之中遇罗宾  -我曰 善 乃识其窈窕欲炮之
Ted saw Robin across a crowded room, and I said, "Oh, yeah,
然泰爱慕之心如金石
you just know she likes it dirty," But Ted really liked her
遂举 否遇泰耶
so we played "Have you met Ted?"
二人遂共进晚餐 泰送罗返 是当吻别
They went to dinner, he walked her home, shoulda kissed her,
未然 恶也 后泰窃其青号 返
didn't-- lame-- so he stole a smurf penis, went back
当吻 未然 恶
to her place, should've kissed her, didn't-- lame.
泰举盛会三 终吻于舍顶
He threw three parties, they kissed on the roof,
然未正道也 大恶
but decided to be friends-- lame--
一日 泰欲携罗共赴友之大婚
then Ted wanted to take Robin to a wedding,
罗未至 泰独往而识维
she couldn't go, he went alone and met Victoria,
然亦未吻之 噫 泰德者 卢瑟也
didn't kiss her either-- lame-- not a great closer, Ted--
然泰终如愿 始正道
but he finally kissed her, they started dating,
维往德意志 泰吻罗 甩维
she went to Germany, Ted kissed Robin, lost Victoria,
泰行祈雨舞 得罗 然终分
Ted did a rain dance, got Robin, Ted and Robin broke up,
罗徙南美 与一拉丁渣渣返
Robin moved to Brazil, came back with a Latin stud,
泰妒 纹一媚记 虽未与主线关联
Ted got jealous, got a tramp stamp, not really relevant
然多多益善乎
to the story I just like mentioning that
吾炮罗 泰割席
as much as possible, I hooked up with Robin, Ted and I stopped
泰遇车祸 遂重和
being friends, Ted got hit by a bus, we made up...
吾始追罗 吾长肉千斤 罗恢恢疑秃
Robin and I started dating, I got fat, her hair fell out.
吾分 罗与唐甚密 吾追诺
We broke up, Robin dated Don, I dated Nora,
与罗红杏出墙 遂弃诺
cheated on her with Robin, I dumped Nora,
罗与凯甚欢 然好景不长
Robin dated Kevin, but not for long,
后吾识汝于佾 汝得吾祖上之手表
and then I met you and you took my grandpa's watch
然爱慕之心不可控也
but I fell in love with you anyway,
汝准放气于厅堂 吾求婚
and you let me fart in front of you and I asked you to marry me
汝准 后往马府探新生
and you said yes and we came over here to meet little Marvin
以上
and that's everything!
哦 对了 我参加价格猜猜猜赢了个甲壳虫车子哟
Also I went on the Price Is Right and won a dune buggy.
别了 巴尼
Goodbye, Barney.
别了是什么意思 我不是
Good... I j...
她同意你在她面前放屁了
She lets you fart in front of her?
巴尼
Barney...
把她追回来 速度
you go get that girl.
什么情况
Oh, God!
你不能告诉任何人你见过我
You cannot tell anyone that you saw me.
我今天不能结婚
I cannot get married today!
克劳斯
Klaus?
嗯 我有点乱
Oh, I'm a mess.
我在衣帽间吐了一地 然后嫁祸给某个熊孩子
I threw up in the cloakroom, I blamed a small child.
我不能结婚
I cannot get married.
我留了张字条
I left a note.
不错哦 不是每个人都想得到的哟
Good for you. Not everyone thinks of that.
哪个煞笔不留条的
Who doesn't leave a note?
这叫基本礼节懂不
It's common courtesy.
太谢谢了
Thank you!
你知道现在几点吗
Do you have the time? Um...
嗯 七点二十
Yeah, it's 20 after 7:00.
唔 很 好
Ah, sehr gut.
我还能赶得上八点五分的回城的车
I can still make the 8:05 back to the city.
拜拜
Auf wiedersehen!
我一瞬间恍然大悟
And suddenly it hit me:
一个免除对维多利亚任何责难的妙招
a way to absolve Victoria of any blame.
只是我必须得爬上那下水道
All I had to do was climb that drainpipe.
什么 不 克劳斯 不
What? No, Klaus, no.
尼玛快点 懒鬼 是时候去
Mach schnell, sleepyhead, it's time to...
我知道你和巴尼的事了
I know about you and Barney.
谁告诉她的
Who told her?!
你们啊
You guys did.
天 睡觉去行不
God, go to sleep.
好 在我们找到抖落秘密的真凶之前谁也不准走
Okay, no one is going anywhere until we find out who told you.
你看
Look...
我和罗宾已经不可能了
there is nothing going on between me and Robin.
我凭什么相信你
And why should I believe that?
呃 先说一句 我有男朋友了
Well, for starters, I have a boyfriend.
不 罗宾 你不用这么做
No, Robin, you don't have to do this.
谎言已经泛滥了
There've been enough lies.
说的是真的
I'm not lying.
他叫尼克
His name is Nick.
我怕出岔子都没告诉大家
I didn't want to jinx it by telling everyone,
所以我就跟马修莉莉说了
so I just told Marshall and Lily.
告诉他们吧 二位
You can tell 'em, guys.
我们刚刚才讨论过的
We were just talking about this earlier today.
好吧 我想说的是
Okay, well, what I was saying is...
我不想把巴尼追回来 因为我现在跟尼克在一起了
I have no desire to get Barney back because I'm with Nick now
而且 呃 姐不想那么三俗
and, well, I don't want to be crude,
姐只想整天都舔他的腹肌
but I want to spend all day licking his abs.
你们明白了吗
Do you understand?
嗯嗯 当然明白
Yes! God, yes!
你不用多费口舌了 妹子
You are preaching to the choir, sister.
我同意
I stand by it.
伙计们 没事儿
Guys, it's okay.
你们刚为人父母
You're new parents.
你们只是得睡会儿觉
You just need to get some sleep.
我们没事
We're fine!
当父母真很难
This is hard, guys.
真的很难
Really hard.
喔 老天 坚持住
Oh, God! Stay with me.
坚持住
Stay with me.
快去照顾你们的宝宝
Go get your baby. Yeah.
你看 我真不在乎你现在有了男朋友
Look, it doesn't matter that you have a boyfriend.
我在乎的是你是不是
I'm always gonna be wondering if you secretly
还对巴尼有感情
still have feelings for Barney.
我才不在乎那个人是谁
I don't care who this guy is.
好吧 我们没问题了
Okay, we're good.
好吧
Okay, well,
多亏我早下班过来
I'm glad I left work early for this.
罗宾 也许我们一会儿得讨论下
Robin, maybe later we can discuss the meaning
"紧急情况"这个词和
of the word "emergency" and the phrase
"被车压住"这两个词的意思
"Trapped under a car."
-好吧 -好
Okay. Okay.
你知道他有小细腿
You know he has chicken legs.
跟小鸡一样的细腿儿
Little tiny chicken legs.
你们看到了 对吧
You guys saw those, right?
亲爱的 我去吧台躺下让尼克从我肚脐眼里喝酒
Honey, it's not cheating if I lie down on the bar
这不算偷腥吧
and let Nick do a shot from my belly button, right?
怎么个情况
Say what now?
巴尼同意喽
Barney's on board!
尼克 你慢走
Nick, hold on!
谢谢你今天帮我
Thanks for your help today.
没问题
Yeah, sure.
只是 看到你那么轻易地就把我们恋爱时的所有东西都处理掉
Although, it, uh, kind of sucked seeing how easy it was
真的很伤我心 真的
for you to throw away everything from our relationship.
我...我可做不出来
I... I could never do that.
西14大街 622号
622 West 14th Street.
就这样 我和维多利亚又回到了出发点
And so, Victoria and I were back where we started.
但有一些事情却在我脑中挥之不去
But there was something I couldn't get off my mind...
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
呃 不好意思
Uh, excuse me.
嘿 是你
Oh, hey, it's you.
好吧 你得听我说
Ja, okay, I'm not sure what kind of vibe
我不知道我之前是不是让你产生什么错觉
I was giving off before,but I am not interested
但我绝对不是对你感兴趣 明白吗
in your schnitzel, okay?
不 不 不 不 不 不是那样
No, no, no, no, no-- God, no.
我就是有个小问题
I-I just have one quick question:
维多利亚是个超棒的姑娘
Victoria seems like a great girl.
你为什么不愿意娶她呢
Why wouldn't you want to marry her?
呃 维多利亚她 她棒呆了
Ach, okay,
Victoria is wunderbar.
不好意思 棒呆了意思就是好极了
I'm sorry, wunderbar is the German word for wonderful.
是 哈 我知道
Yeah, no, I know.
喔 你讲德语
Oh, you speak German?
不
No...
不 不 不
No, no, no...
不 我只懂那一个词
No, just-just-just the one word.
哦 哦
Oh. Oh.
啊 维多利亚
Ah... Okay, Victoria.
德语里有一个词 Lebenslangerschicksalsschatz.
There is a word in German: Lebenslangerschicksalsschatz.
最贴切的翻译是
And the closest translation would be...
"真命天女"
"Lifelong Treasure of Destiny."
的确 维多利亚棒呆了
And Victoria is wunderbar,
但她不是我“真命天女”
but she is not my Lebenslangerschicksalsschatz.
她是我的Beinaheleidenschaftsgegenstand
She is my Beinaheleidenschaftsgegenstand,
你明白吗
you know?
你知道棒呆了
You know wunderbar
却不知道Beinaheleidenschaftsgegenstand
but you don't know Beinaheleidenschaftsgegenstand?
这词我们幼儿园就学过
That is something we learn in kindergarten.
不好意思 "幼儿园"这个词在德语里是――
I'm sorry, "kindergarten" is the German word for--
啊 啊 我知道的那个词
No, no, I know that one.
好吧
Oh, okay.
但你不知道Beinaheleidenschaftsgegenstand
But you don't know Beinaheleidenschaftsgegenstand?
你对德语的认识还真那么参差不齐
You are maddeningly inconsistent.
Beinaheleidenschaftsgegenstand的意思是
It means...
这就是你几乎想要的东西
"The thing that is almost the thing that you want...
但似乎又不是
...but it's not quite."
这就像维多利亚于我
Das ist Victoria to me.
你怎么知道她不是真命天女
How do you know she's not Lebenslangerschicksalsschatz?
我是说 也许随着时光流逝 她会变得更像
I mean, maybe as the years go by, she'll get
真命天女
Lebenslangerschicksalsschatz -ier.
哦 不不不
Oh, nein, nein, nein.
真命天女不是会随着时间变化的
Lebenslangerschicksalsschatz is not something
某种东西
that develops over time.
这是一种稍瞬即逝的东西
It is something that happens instantaneously.
它穿过你
It courses through you
就像风暴之后的河水
like the water of a river after a storm...
...在同时使你充盈 又使你空虚
...filling you and emptying you all at once.
你在你身体内
You feel it throughout your body...
你的手中
In your hands...
你的心里
In your heart...
你的胃里...
in your stomach...
你的皮肤里...
in your skin...
当然还有在你的Schlauchmachendejungen里感受到它
Of course you feel it in your Schlauchmachendejungen.
原谅我用法语
Pardon my French.
你对某人有过这种感觉吗
Have you ever felt this way about someone?
是 我想是的
Yeah, I think so.
如果你还得考虑 那你还没感受到
If you have to think about it, you have not felt it.
而你确定你会在未来找到吗
And you're absolutely sure you'll find that someday?
当然
Of course.
每个人最终都能找得到
Everyone does eventually.
你只是永远不知何时何地
You just never know when or where.
他是对的
And he was right.
不幸的是
Unfortunately, the "When" Of it was still
“何时”仍然有点遥远
a little ways down the road.
但是“何地”呢
But the "Where" Of it?
哦 不要忘了你吉他
Oh, and don't forget your guitar.